<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Mostly Curious Blog</title>
 <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-04-11T23:50:45-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://mostlycurious.com/</id>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Mostlycurious Search</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2015/04/11/mostlycurious-search/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2015/04/11/mostlycurious-search</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mostlycurious.com is a static Jekyll site hosted on Github.  This has been pretty convenient compared to my prior efforts, which have included Posterous, Tumblr, Ghost. One thing I have always wanted to include was a site-specific search bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a new problem, and a quick search led me to a previously answered &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10131541/how-can-i-add-a-site-search-feature-to-a-jekyll-blog&quot;&gt;Stackoverflow post&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://cse.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google custom search&lt;/a&gt;, because it seems pretty easy for a first attempt (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-04-11-google-custom-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Output script&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cohen's D Visualized</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/science/2015/04/03/cohen%27s-d-visualized/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/science/2015/04/03/cohen's-d-visualized</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kristoffer Magnussen has a neat blog about statistics and psychology at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rpsychologist.com/d3/cohend/&quot;&gt;R &amp;lt;- Psychologist&lt;/a&gt;.  In particular, he has a very useful visualization of a metric called Cohen&#39;s d.  Even if you know what that is, it&#39;s very helpful to have a quick tool on hand without having to calculate anything.  All of the visualization appears to be made from &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org&quot;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt;, which is becoming a standard for showing your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-04-03-cohen-d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Matlab Files On Github</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/productivity/2015/03/28/my-matlab-files-on-github/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/productivity/2015/03/28/my-matlab-files-on-github</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, I&#39;ll be distributing various Matlab programs that I&#39;ve used to analyze scientific data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Windows+p</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/productivity/2015/03/25/windows%2BP/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/productivity/2015/03/25/windows+P</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Windows 8 has a nice shortcut, that&#39;s actually been on previous versions, but I&#39;ve just discovered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Windows logo + p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-03-25-screen-options.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one shortcut, by quickly allowing you to toggle between duplicating and extending across monitors, simultaneously kills two of my annoyances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever had to give a presentation and not be able to control your presentation view? (perhaps due to some ATI or nVIDIA driver that overrides Windows native display control)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever use Chrome remote desktop to a machine with dual monitors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia - Sleepio</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/2015/03/02/cognitive-behavioral-therapy-for-insomnia-sleepio/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-02T22:42:14-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/2015/03/02/cognitive-behavioral-therapy-for-insomnia-sleepio</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-03-02-jawbone-email-sleepio.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is an image of a Jawbone email, advertising some new products in their space.  Of particular interest was Sleepio, a company that runs a sleep improvement program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sleepio.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and was welcomed with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can we help you sleep better?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site welcomes you to take a quick survery about your sleep, and in my opinion ask the correct questions about the status of your sleep.  Questions like how long it takes for you to fall asleep, or whether you feel restless at night. After some numbers crunching, the Sleepio surveymonkey appears to phenotype your sleep profile, and compute whether it&#39;s product will help you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have helped 69% of people with sleep like yours improve their sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sleepio product is based on something called cognitive behavioral therapy.  In this instance, the therapy aims to break a presumed bad cycle of negative sleep thoughts leading to negative emotions regarding sleep, which inevitably result in poor sleep behaviors. Of course, this will only work to the extent that there isn&#39;t an underlying physiological reason for poor sleep (e.g. sleep apnea, or a truly unique melantonin brain circuit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product consists of 6 or so online weekly therapy sessions, that first suggest practical lifestyle changes to improve your sleep. Something like, turn off all the lights before you sleep. Next the sessions give participants strategies for breaking the association of negative emotions with sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now this all sounds like psychotherapy.  But here&#39;s where technology comes in: you can use the Jawbone up to track your progress. For the first, you have some feedback on your performance that you cant track alongside your lifestyle adjustments. This sounds simple enough to try before resorting to pharmacological interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Multitasking hurts your effective IQ</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/learning/productivity/2015/02/16/multitasking-hurts-your-effective-iq/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-16T20:17:46-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/learning/productivity/2015/02/16/multitasking-hurts-your-effective-iq</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/science/2015/jan/18/modern-world-bad-for-brain-daniel-j-levitin-organized-mind-information-overload&quot;&gt;The Guardian has an article by Daniel Levitan&lt;/a&gt; that describes the negatives of multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41fd-uSM0QL._AA160_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Organized Mind&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ekmiller.org/&quot;&gt;Earl Miller&lt;/a&gt; at MIT:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people think they’re multitasking, they’re actually just switching from one task to another very rapidly. And every time they do, there’s a cognitive cost in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we multitask when there&#39;s this switching cost? Our brain releases opioids for the snippets of novelty associated with each individual task. And that could be more valuable to our brains, then the rewards of completing a single, longer task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s worse, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poldracklab.stanford.edu/&quot;&gt;Russ Poldrack&lt;/a&gt;, does fMRI experiments at Stanford, and proposes that multitasking (er, watching TV) during study time could lead to suboptimal memory storage in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the article focuses on how our most accepted forms of communication (email, text) are inherently configured to promote multitasking and information overload. But there is one quote that sticks out in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;‘When trying to concentrate on a task, an unread email in your inbox can reduce your effective IQ by 10 points.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Corning Gorilla Glass</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2015/02/08/corning-gorilla-glass/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-08T03:08:05-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2015/02/08/corning-gorilla-glass</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corninggorillaglass.com/&quot;&gt;Corning Gorilla Glass&lt;/a&gt; is the surface for most typical cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it&#39;s made: &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ishizuka.co.jp/english/material/images/07_img02.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
The glass is manufactured by incubation in a bath of hot potassium solution. Sodium ions in the glass are exchanged with larger, heavier potassium ions. This results in compressed, chemically strengthened glass.  It&#39;s actually a refinement of old technology that dates back to the 1960s, and similar techniques have been used to alter the optical properties of glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it&#39;s branded:&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.corninggorillaglass.com/uploads/kcfinder/images/VidVic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object id=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&amp;isUI=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;flashVars&quot; value=&quot;videoId=713927919001&amp;playerID=625505125001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAkVHRxYE~,tk4-uogNPTL8DvW4rWbX-hN95sv6ZKg3&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;base&quot; value=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;seamlesstabbing&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;swLiveConnect&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&amp;isUI=1&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; flashVars=&quot;videoId=713927919001&amp;playerID=625505125001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAkVHRxYE~,tk4-uogNPTL8DvW4rWbX-hN95sv6ZKg3&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; base=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; name=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; seamlesstabbing=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; allowScriptAccess=&quot;always&quot; swLiveConnect=&quot;true&quot; pluginspage=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;



</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Choosing a good team</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/productivity/2015/02/06/qualities-of-good-teams/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-06T04:09:33-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/productivity/2015/02/06/qualities-of-good-teams</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s an opinion piece in the New York Times on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/18/opinion/sunday/why-some-teams-are-smarter-than-others.html&quot;&gt;why some teams are smarter than others&lt;/a&gt;. The authors, gave a large number of teams a set of real-world challenges, and examined their performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the insignificant factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IQ scores&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extroversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;motivation to contribute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here are the factors that did matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no individual dominates the group discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;number of women on the team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to read others&#39; emotions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That last point is interesting, because the authors found the same results, with remote teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What makes teams smart must be not just the ability to read facial expressions, but a more general ability, known as “Theory of Mind,” to consider and keep track of what other people feel, know and believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Structured procrastination</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/productivity/2015/02/06/structured-procrastination/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-06T03:50:13-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/productivity/2015/02/06/structured-procrastination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;the procrastinator can be motivated to do difficult, timely and important tasks, as long as these tasks are a way of not doing something more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41Ylf6lZRvL._SX258_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this a few years ago in graduate school, from a website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://structuredprocrastination.com/blog/&quot;&gt;structuredprocrastination&lt;/a&gt;. Of course I was looking for ways to get my work done. The author turned out to be a professor at the very school I was at!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a tip he wrote to be particularly useful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fifth, make To Do Lists that break up your tasks into smaller ones, so you can get the thrill of checking them off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up paying $25 a year for an online To Do List, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rememberthemilk.com&quot;&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt;. For me, it does make alot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Leaving the Cult of Busy</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/productivity/2015/02/02/leaving-the-cult-of-busy/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-02T03:59:24-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/productivity/2015/02/02/leaving-the-cult-of-busy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dina Kaplan has an insightful artice aptly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/thelist/the-cult-of-busy-bbb124caed51&quot;&gt;The Cult of Busy&lt;/a&gt;, which explores whether we are over-allocating our lives to busywork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; If your normal is busy, it’s tough to sit quietly with your thoughts or to really feel what you’re feeling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged.  I find the NYC subway on the way to the West Side YMCA to be my only reprieve.  This will continue to be true, as long as there is no WiFi on the moving train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dina provides one simple task that I&#39;ve distilled to leave the Cult of Busy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could set reasonable goals for each day, then head directly towards them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve always wanted to read, find five minutes each day this week. Next week, find ten. Take it at your own pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Virtual reality with the Unreal Engine 4</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2015/02/01/virtual-reality-with-the-unreal-4-engine/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-01T21:48:28-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2015/02/01/virtual-reality-with-the-unreal-4-engine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The things software engineers can do with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unrealengine.com/showcase?category=Film%20and%20Television&quot;&gt;Unreal Engine 4&lt;/a&gt; are amazing. Below is a still frame from a virtual home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-02-01-unreal-engine.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the creator of the Unreal Engine is Epic Games.  Chinese company Tencent has a large 48.5% stake that costed &gt;$300 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the high-definition video. Definitely looks like money well-spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y6PQ19BEE24&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First post from ghost</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2015/02/01/first-post-from-ghost/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-01T21:25:51-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2015/02/01/first-post-from-ghost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ghost looks great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks alot more convenient to blog.  I had been using Jekyll hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rpjb/rpjb.github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to create a simple static website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key advantage of ghost was simply the quick preview of  the output when drafting in Ghost. Jekyll does have a frontend called &lt;a href=&quot;http://prose.io&quot;&gt;Prose&lt;/a&gt;, but there was a latency on the server end, that I found a bit challenging for the amount of typing errors I typically make.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bill Dement The Father Of Sleep Medicine</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/2014/09/08/bill-dement-the-father-of-sleep-medicine/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/2014/09/08/bill-dement-the-father-of-sleep-medicine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nick Weiler has a new piece in the Stanford Magazine dedicated to the study of sleep (&lt;a href=&quot;https://alumni.stanford.edu/get/page/magazine/article/?article_id=72890&quot;&gt;A Bedtime Story&lt;/a&gt;). Nick presents the career of the key protagonist, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_C._Dement&quot;&gt;Bill Dement&lt;/a&gt;, in entertaining fashion. Professor Dement created the very first sleep laboratory at Stanford in 1970. He studied the relationship between REM sleep and dreams, and was the first to classify the various sleep states in humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do all of this work, Professor Dement had to be able to do continuous physiological monitoring during sleep. Back in the day, this was a non-trivial affair.  With the Sheepdog Sciences headband today, we believe Dr. Dement would have been able to do the majority of his work at the subjects&#39; homes.  This would have reduced the experimental noise arising from the stress of sleeping in a research lab, and probably increased the number of participants in his studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting tidbits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t know what the &quot;right&quot; amount of sleep for humans is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;40 million Americans suffered from chronic sleep disorder (1992 study).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;24 percent of men in an epidemiology study suffered sleep apnea&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Teachers Can Cheat Too</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/learning/2014/09/03/teachers-can-cheat-too/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/learning/2014/09/03/teachers-can-cheat-too</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Education is becoming an increasingly high stress industry in America. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/07/21/wrong-answer?&quot;&gt;Wrong Answers?&lt;/a&gt; in July&#39;s New Yorker details a school that cheated for its students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elementary schools have to meet No Child Left Behind minimum standards for performance. Certain schools have a particularly difficult road to meeting those standards. Independent of whether test scores are an adequate measure of education or student growth, the situation is very stressful for educators in those schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation surely feels out of the educator&#39;s control. At a very minimum, the students, not the teachers must perform well on the exam. The parents must suitably prepare their children for learning each day before they head to school. Teachers rely on their colleagues that teach earlier levels, so that the students are prepared to learn new material.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Blue Light Danger</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/2014/09/03/blue-light-danger/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/2014/09/03/blue-light-danger</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2014/09/01/what-is-the-blue-light-from-our-screens-really-doing-to-our-eyes&quot;&gt;article on the effects of blue light on our bodies&lt;/a&gt;. The basic ideas are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blue light alters your production of melatonin at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern phones, tablets, laptops, and TVs have significant blue light emission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delayed production of melatonin are thought to correlate with insomnia, diabetes, some cancers, early onset macular degeneration&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Light As A Type Of Medication</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/2014/08/18/light-as-a-type-of-medication/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/2014/08/18/light-as-a-type-of-medication</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a postdoc and sometimes have the misfortune of having to work deep into the night to get my job done. I&#39;ve always wondered how cool it would be to not get sleepy or hungry, and just keep going. Is there anything I could do doing what I want to be doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Gene Block had a nice tidbit in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/articles/our-internal-sleep-clocks-are-out-of-sync-1408036238&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research is beginning to show how we can regulate the various internal clocks that make up the circadian system. In addition, the advent of inexpensive wrist and pocket monitors that can monitor activity and inactivity may eventually allow individuals to &quot;self-medicate&quot; by optimizing their exposure to light and minimizing sleep disruption while they work and travel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While alot of people get along fine by consuming caffeine, as a coffee non-drinker I can attest to having used light to &quot;self-medicate.&quot;  When it&#39;s late at night, and I want to keep working, I prefer to use full spectrum light bulbs (as opposed to the soft white variety).  Amazon ships a bright compact fluorescent lightbulb (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Utilitech-4-Pack-23-Watt-Standard-Daylight/dp/B00A9V7RA6/ref=sr_1_3?s=lamps-light&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=undefined&amp;amp;sr=1-3&amp;amp;keywords=CFL++5000k&quot;&gt;5000K, 100W equivalent&lt;/a&gt;) that definiitely keeps me awake. Unless I&#39;m sleep deprived over several weeks, the light effect on me is sufficient to keep me active 3-5 hours past my typical sleeping time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, when I&#39;m sleepy, I try to minimize the potential for having bright light come into my room.  The best method I&#39;ve seen is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Solid-Thermal-Insulated-Blackout-Curtain/dp/B001A63XTS&quot;&gt;blackout curtains&lt;/a&gt; which are also easily available on Amazon.  In this case, I can have a nice deep sleep for many more hours past my typical awakening time.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-08-18-blackout-curtain.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blackout curtains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sleep Inertia</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/learning/2014/05/13/sleep-inertia/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/learning/2014/05/13/sleep-inertia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/elements/2013/12/science-of-sleep-trouble-with-snooze-buttons.html&quot;&gt;article from the New Yorker by Maria Konnikova&lt;/a&gt; has an interesting introduction to the concept of sleep inertia. The time between the moment you wake up in the morning until the moment you are really awake is called sleep inertia.  And it can be really bad.  It turns out that our brains take some time to get into awake mode, and as a result our memory, and ability to perform are negatively effected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a good quote from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.colorado.edu/intphys/research/sleep.html&quot;&gt;Professor Kenneth Wright&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cognition is best several hours prior to habitual sleep time, and worst near habitual wake time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a mission critical activity, you&#39;re going to want to minimize sleep inertia. To do this, you&#39;ll want to wake up naturally.  And that&#39;s affected by natural light, and your own internal alarm clock. We can each appreciate that our bodies are very different, so each person will need to emperically determine the best sleep habits.  And contrary to what your mother may tell you, sleep duration doesn&#39;t necessarily lead to the best outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bruce Alberts Avoids The Pitfalls In Science</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/04/25/bruce-alberts-avoids-the-pitfalls-in-science/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/04/25/bruce-alberts-avoids-the-pitfalls-in-science</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following are excerpts from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v431/n7012/full/4311041a.html&quot;&gt;small essay&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Alberts (the author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Biology-Cell-Bruce-Alberts/dp/0815341059&quot;&gt;Molecular Biology of the Cell&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the competitive side of science:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had witnessed the frustration of scientists who were pursuing obvious experiments that were simultaneously being carried out in other laboratories. These scientists were constantly in a race. It had always seemed to me that, even if they were able to publish their results six months before a competing laboratory, they were unlikely to make truly unique contributions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one-sided experiments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My approach had been that of predicting how a particular biological process might work and then taking years to test whether my guess might be right. This was enormously risky. The good news was that I was carrying out experiments that were different from those being done by everyone else. The problem was that these tests could produce only a ‘yes’ or ‘no’ answer. If ‘yes’, I might be able to add something unique to the world’s store of scientific knowledge. But if ‘no’, I would learn nothing of real value&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his strategy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would look for a unique experimental approach, but one that would have a high probability of increasing our knowledge of the natural world, regard- less of the experimental results obtained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Airline Fare Predictors And User Preferences</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/04/21/airline-fare-predictors-and-user-preferences/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/04/21/airline-fare-predictors-and-user-preferences</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/when-to-hold-out-for-a-lower-airfare/?utm_source=digg&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot;&gt;Kaiser Fung has a great article&lt;/a&gt; on using Big Data to predict airfare prices. He gives a great overview of Bing (Farecast) and Kayak regarding how they try to provide value for their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are a few of this conclusions:
1. There is quite a bit of spread in the eventual savings you get using a fare predictor.
2. When Kayak says to buy, it&#39;s usually the best you can do as prices indeed rise days after. This is good.
3. When Kayak says to wait, you might not actually see the price drop in subsequent days. This is bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might wonder, why might this be?  And the answer has to do with what the customer wants.
A customer may want to be certain about a Kayak buy signal (high true positive rate), and usually doesn&#39;t track prices after buying, so he tolerates erroneous buy signals (high false positive rate). What the customer absolutely doesn&#39;t want to see is a Kayak wait signal, when in fact fares are rising on subsequent days.  So Kayak tries to maximize true positive rate and minimize false negative rates. Hence they optimize sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Bing (Farecast), they try to minimize the number of buy signals based on giving the impression that whenever a buy signal is present it is very meaningful (high true positive rate and low false positive rate). Hence they optimize precision (or positive predictive value).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And at the end of the day, all of this has to do with the perceived value to the customer. A conservative customer may choose for better precision or sensitivity.  Maybe the ultimate solution would be to let the user decide with a slider bar....&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Changing Taste Preference For Electric Eels</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/04/12/changing-taste-preference-for-electric-eels/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/04/12/changing-taste-preference-for-electric-eels</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a youtube video of an alligator trying to eat an electric eel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/d01wLnN689g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It sure looks like the alligator died from electric shock, while the eel presumably died from a permanent crimping via aligator jaw.  And I wondered to myself, if such encounters are lethal to the eel, does it serve an evolutionary advantage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibility 1: maybe the encounters aren&#39;t always lethal, and the alligator now knows for the rest of its life not to eat the eel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibility 2: encounters are lethal, but passerby alligators rubberneck and now know for the rest of their lives not to eat the eel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibility 3: encounters are lethal, and over the thousands of years, all alligators that have a taste preference for eels are killed, a selection pressure of sorts. Thus whatever genetic attributes that confer electric eel preference are removed from the genetic pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which is true here, but very interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cleaning Unfinished Wood</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/04/10/cleaning-unfinished-wood/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/04/10/cleaning-unfinished-wood</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been looking for a good answer to cleaning unfinished wood.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20091129101828AAyhO4F&quot;&gt;Yahoo answers&lt;/a&gt; has a good response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For unfinished wood, the best way to clean and get all the dirt, grime, fingerprints, etc off is to use a very fine sandpaper. You can get it at any hardware store - look for 400 grit. This is so fine that it won&#39;t leave sanding marks on the furniture, but it will clear off all the dirt and oils. Check especially down at the bottom of the piece for scuffmarks from shoes, etc and get those off, and don&#39;t forget to clean any wooden door or drawer pulls. Don&#39;t be afraid to put a little muscle into it if you run into stubborn marks or dirt. 400 grit is superfine, it won&#39;t hurt anything. Once you&#39;re done sanding, you can just wipe the piece with a damp cloth to remove any leftover sanding dust. Voila. Beautiful and ready for sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Optimal Sleep Amount</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/2014/04/02/optimal-sleep-amount/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/2014/04/02/optimal-sleep-amount</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s an article on Quora asking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Sleep/How-can-I-determine-what-my-personal-basal-sleep-requirement-is&quot;&gt;&quot;How can I determine what my personal basal sleep requirement is?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; The short answer is 7-9 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However there was an interesting answer that warrants some further thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists have found a gene that seems to allow some of us to get as much sleep as we need in as little time as 6 hours. But only 3% of us have that gene. Most likely you&#39;re in the other 97%. And if you&#39;re getting less than 6 hours, you are building up a big &quot;sleep debt&quot; in your body even if you have got the gene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tracked down the paper from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neugenes.org/outreach.htm&quot;&gt;lab of Ying-Hui Fu&lt;/a&gt; at UCSF. The paper, titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/325/5942/866&quot;&gt;The Transcriptional Repressor DEC2 Regulates Sleep Length in Mammals&lt;/a&gt;, identifies a single mutation (a C to G DNA point mutation) on a gene that gives its carriers the ability to naturally wake-up earlier,as they require less sleep.  The paper goes on to recapitulate the effects of this mutation in mice, because we can easily modify their genomes. The only issue, is that mice don&#39;t really sleep the same way humans do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it&#39;s interesting, because there are now technologies that can be used to easily screen for this mutation, as well as potentially &lt;a href=&quot;http://zlab.mit.edu&quot;&gt;edit the gene&lt;/a&gt; in humans. But at the same time, I&#39;ll continue to enjoy my sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Solarized Colors</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/web/2014/03/22/solarized-colors/"/>
   <updated>2014-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/web/2014/03/22/solarized-colors</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-03-22-solarized.png&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; alt=&quot;Solarized&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized&quot;&gt;Solarized&lt;/a&gt; has a nice set of colors that are optimized for your viewing pleasure. The colors are somewhat muted, but very legible, and easily distinguish text. It happens to coincidentally be very similar to a color palette I use for my presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-03-22-keynote-colors.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Keynote color palette&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like having a go-to set of colors so that I don&#39;t waste hours deciding.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Start School Later</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/sleep/learning/2014/03/16/Start-school-later/"/>
   <updated>2014-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/sleep/learning/2014/03/16/Start-school-later</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-03-16-clock.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Set your alarm later&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog article from the New York Times (&lt;a href=&quot;http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/03/13/to-keep-teenagers-alert-schools-let-them-sleep-in/&quot;&gt;To Keep Teenagers Alert, Schools Start to Let Them Sleep In&lt;/a&gt;) observes a study in which high schools with later start times (say 8am, as opposed to 7:20am) tend to have students that had lower commute accidents, better attendance, and possibly better grades/test scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might ask, if the day starts later, won&#39;t the kids stay up even later? It turns out that physiologically, younger adults have preset programs that induce sleepiness much later in the night. Shifting the start time of school simply matches their obligations to their physiology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But possibly the most important aspect of this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many researchers say that quality sleep directly affects learning because people store new facts during deep-sleep cycles. During the rapid-eye-movement phases, the brain is wildly active, sorting and categorizing the day’s data. The more sleep a teenager gets, the &gt;better the information is absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at the end of the day, it&#39;s okay to go to sleep if you&#39;re tired. It&#39;ll help your brain for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Too much data</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/02/19/too-much-data/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/02/19/too-much-data</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-02-19-resonate.png&quot; alt=&quot;Resonate, by Nancy Duarte&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m flipping through Resonate, by Nancy Duarte.  It&#39;s a guide to bringing out the story in presentations.  As an engineer masquerading as a scientist, I find myself looking at the data, rather than looking at the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/01/too-much-data-leads-to-not-enough-belief.html&quot;&gt;one quote&lt;/a&gt; that Nancy uses from Seth Godin, was particular insightful to me:
The problem is this: no spreadsheet, no bibliography and no list of resources is sufficient proof to someone who chooses not to believe. The skeptic will always find a reason, even if it&#39;s one the rest of us don&#39;t think is a good one. Relying too much on proof distracts you from the real mission--which is emotional connection.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>the Sheepdog Sciences word cloud</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2014/01/31/sheepdog-wordcloud/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/01/31/sheepdog-wordcloud</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2014-01-31-sds-word-cloud.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sheepdog Sciences word cloud&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;made by Todd Anderson, co-founder of Sheepdog Sciences&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Digital enhancements</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/11/19/photoshop/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/11/19/photoshop</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17j5QzF3kqE&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;Body Evolution - Model Before and After&lt;/a&gt;&quot;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-19-before.png&quot; alt=&quot;Before&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-19-after.png&quot; alt=&quot;After&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How we expect to get rich</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/11/14/getlucky/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/11/14/getlucky</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ramit Sethi has a blog called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwillteachyoutoberich.com&quot;&gt;I Will Teach You to Be Rich&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, which provides aton of interesting information about maybe not how to get rich, but how to make your skills work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular factoid that he recently emailed out shows our collective optimism at its best:
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-14-berich.png&quot; alt=&quot;Get rich by getting lucky&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Market research</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/11/11/marketresearch/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/11/11/marketresearch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-12-delta-twitter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Delta&#39;s Twitter feed&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-12-delta-united.png&quot; alt=&quot;Delta / United stock prices year to date&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I like pig butts</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/11/10/pig-butts/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/11/10/pig-butts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-11-pig-butts.png&quot; alt=&quot;I like pig butts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tanga.com/deals/81ac27831d6a/i-like-pig-butts-t-shirt&quot;&gt;Purchase from tanga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New dell laptop that smells awful</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/11/07/Dell-cat-pee/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/11/07/Dell-cat-pee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a great find by my co-founder Alex. There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.community.dell.com/support-forums/laptop/f/3518/t/19512174.aspx&quot;&gt;Dell forum thread&lt;/a&gt; that concerns new laptop purchases, that have rather smelly palm rests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;tomcats litter box&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;cat pee&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I thought for sure that the guy in the next cube who has a cat
brought the cat into work and it urinated on the floor&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;It&#39;s humiliating in class&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;a pack of well hydrated feral cats have used it for target practice&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;it&#39;s almost burning my eyes&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, the obligatory &lt;strong&gt;grumpy&lt;/strong&gt; cat meme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-07-catmeme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grumpy cat doesn&#39;t like new Dell laptop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&#39;t worry, following standard forum protocol, there&#39;s an accepted solution. Kudos to Dell, rather than not acknowledging the problem (as to compared to say, Apple)
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-11-07-dell-fix.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dell fix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Unsubscribe to The Children's Place</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/10/27/Best-Unsubscribe-Page/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/10/27/Best-Unsubscribe-Page</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-10-27-childrensplaceunsubscribe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Unsubscribe screenshot. (from The Children&#39;s Place)&quot; /&gt;
When a visitor unsubscribes to your website, it&#39;s never a good thing. But at least one can be light-hearted about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Calorie counting at the Outback Steakhouse</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/09/14/outback/"/>
   <updated>2013-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/09/14/outback</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since college in Champaign-Urbana, I&#39;ve been a big fan of the Bloomin&#39; Onion at the Outback Steakhouse. Nestled in the middle of nowhere far far away from campus, my roommates and I would go there every few months for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-09-14-uiuc%20outback.png&quot; alt=&quot;Go north for steak.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, this image was made entirely by OSX programs. Using the screen clipping tool, I took an image of google maps, and then put the clipboard into a new image on preview. Then I used their annotation tool, which seems very vector-like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was more than a decade ago, and calorie counting wasn&#39;t that big a deal back then. Fast forward to current times, and every restaurant in New York City now has some calorie range for each item on their menus. About two years ago I found myself in the Manhattan Outback to watch a Florida game I believe. Of course, we ordered the big Bloomin&#39; Onion. But I was astonished to find out that one big fried onion was nearly 2000 calories!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-09-14-outbackmenu.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;3/4 of your daily calorie intake before the main course.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not to be outdone, are the chicken wings, another 2k of calories. Now I believe I shared the onion and the wings with one other person, and that was before the steaks we ordered. Since saving this picture of the menu, I haven&#39;t been back to an Outback Steakhouse. If I ever do return, I&#39;m bringing 5 companions to share the onion.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Going for distance</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/06/23/going-for-distance/"/>
   <updated>2013-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/06/23/going-for-distance</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my last trip to the Philippines, I came across an interesting seafood restaurant. As I walked in, I was greeted by two statues of men posing as they urinated into a koi pond.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-06-23-statue1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arch back for optimal trajectory?&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-06-23-statue2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keep hands back for balance!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Old guys can still play</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/04/11/David-Beckham-still-runs/"/>
   <updated>2013-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/04/11/David-Beckham-still-runs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-04-11-beckham-runs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Distance run after first half of play. (from New York Times)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one thinks of David Beckham, the free kick ability is one of the first things to come into mind. Now that was about a decade ago. Now, at 37 years old, he has gone through a few seasons in the MLS, which isn&#39;t exactly the equivalent of the English Premier League. Well, he now plays for PSG, the top French team at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week ago, he started a Champions League match against Barcelona. I watched the replay of the first leg, and was shocked at Beckham&#39;s statistics after one half. Even as a deep lying old man, he still managed to log the most distance run by any of the players on the field. This is more than the distance run by the famous high-work rate Barcelona players such as Xavi and Iniesta. Moreover, many of the players are at least 15 years younger than him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is this a first? In terms of age, probably not. 38 year old Paul Scholes comes to mind, who covered 8.5km in 79 minutes of play against Galatasaray  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uefa.com/uefachampionsleague/season=2013/matches/live/day=1/session=2/match=2009494/index.html&quot;&gt;Champions League match stats&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Regenerating mice</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/04/04/regenerating-mice/"/>
   <updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/04/04/regenerating-mice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.6582.1348672991!/image/Seifert2.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_300/Seifert2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of injured spiny mouse (from Nature)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/african-spiny-mice-can-regrow-lost-skin-1.11488&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt; has a report on a mammal that can regenerate tissue. The African spiny mouse can take some serious damage, and heal quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Flight of the dragonflies.</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/04/04/dragonfly-neurons/"/>
   <updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/04/04/dragonfly-neurons</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-04-04-evading_dragonfly.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dragonfly evading bullfrog. (from New York Times)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/02/science/dragonflies-natures-deadly-drone-but-prettier.html&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; has a writeup on the predatory abilities of a dragonfly.  Only 16 neurons are required for the dragonfly to track and calculate trajectories to reach its prey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a dragonfly has four wings which confers extraordinary flight abilities. But, even when handicapped by losing a single wing, it is still able eat its fly food mid-flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One researcher at Janelia Farms in particular attaches electronic sensor backpacks to more finely measure flight trajectories and most likely in the near future, neuronal activity during flight.  Here&#39;s a three year old &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/16298313&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; from that lab.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fonts for mostlycurious</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/03/23/google-web-fonts/"/>
   <updated>2013-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/03/23/google-web-fonts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-02-23-googlewebfont.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lato font by Lukasz Dziedzic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; has a large set of web-optimized, open source fonts, and an easy to use interface to help select that magic one. The fonts load fast, even loading the webpage on a tethered 4g (not LTE) laptop almost as quickly as I can scroll down. When there are 600+ fonts, you&#39;re going to do alot of scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I settled on the Lato font at 400 weight. On my Keynote presentations, I&#39;ve used Helvetica Neue with light weighting since 2009. So I guess I was looking for something similar. I wanted thin lines, which Helvetica Neue does with good effect. However unlike presentations, I presume someone will be reading these paragraphs. So on a browser, perhaps something with a bit larger character spacing would work. Let me know what you think....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-03-23-helvetica-neue.png&quot; alt=&quot;Helvetica Neue Light in Keynote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The good life at Spitbank Fort</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/03/19/spitbank-fort/"/>
   <updated>2013-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/03/19/spitbank-fort</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6b/Guests_Arriving_at_Spitbank_Fort.jpg/300px-Guests_Arriving_at_Spitbank_Fort.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old fort to luxury hotel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new deal on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandaddy.com/jt/hotels/22196/Spitbank_Fort_An_Island_Fortress_That_Thinks_It_s_a_Hotel_Jetset_JT_Hotel&quot;&gt;UrbanDaddy&lt;/a&gt; has would-be luxury travelers vacationing in an old military fort on the English Channel. Back in the 1860&#39;s, this fort was built to protect Portsmouth from presumably invading naval ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 1 million British pounds and 150 years laters, a quick perusal of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spitbankfort.com/&quot;&gt;Spitbank Fort website&lt;/a&gt; shows a legit tourist attraction complete with amenities for corporate events and even weddings!  If you look hard enough on the site, you might actually get an idea of where it is exactly.  In fact this fort is so small, that you can barely distinguish it from nearby boats on the google maps satellite image (green arrow).&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2013-03-19-spitbankfort.png&quot; alt=&quot;A small dot 1km offshore&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Migrating from Posterous to Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/03/17/posterous2jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/03/17/posterous2jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After several years of happily using posterous and it&#39;s easy email-to-blog service, I&#39;ve been forced to seek alternatives as posterous will turn off later next month. This post is my first attempt to blog using Jekyll, a rather straightforward way to communicate on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be trying Jekyll out for a bit.  I basically took the instructions from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.apps.npr.org/2012/11/08/npr-news-apps-blog.html&quot;&gt;NPR blog site&lt;/a&gt;. Please forgive the bare bones nature of the site, we&#39;re under construction. And by that I mean, I&#39;m figuring out how to type in markdown, and actually find some visual inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About Me</title>
   <link href="http://mostlycurious.com/2013/03/17/about/"/>
   <updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.apps.npr.org/2013/03/17/about</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Robert Barretto&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-mug&quot; width=&quot;90&quot; src=&quot;../../../../img/robert.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m the main curator of mostlycurious. I&#39;m a cofounder of sheepdog sciences, where we translate neuroscience research into tools and systems that can improve our everyday lives. I also do basic neuroscience research with Charles Zuker at Columbia University. I am originally from Oak Lawn, a South Side suburb of Chicago. I tend to like my job on most days. Find me on Twitter as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/rpjb&quot;&gt;@rpjb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
