<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mostlycurious</title>
    <description>blog</description>
    <link>http://rpjb.github.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rpjb.github.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Displaying Grouped File Info In Osx</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I often want to check the size of a subset of folders on OS X.  To do this I use finder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-06-11-finder.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shortcut for viewing info in Finder is ⌘+I.  This is great for single files.  But what happens if you want a group of folders (or files)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Result of ⌘+I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-06-11-soloinfo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the summary of a group try the following.&lt;br/&gt;
Result of ⌘+⌥+I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-06-11-groupinfo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/06/11/displaying-grouped-file-info-in-OSX/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/06/11/displaying-grouped-file-info-in-OSX/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kleptomnesia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Grant has an &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/3652127/why-we-steal-ideas/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in Time that explores why we steal others people&#39;s ideas. For those with a cynical eye, stealing is done with intent. But perhaps some thefts are accidental, or beyond conscious thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter kleptomnesia, which is defined as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;generating an idea that you believe is novel, but in fact was created by someone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the root psychological cause?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kleptomnesia happens due to a pragmatic, but peculiar, feature of how human memory is wired. When we encode information, we tend to pay more attention to the content than the source. Once we accept a piece of information as true, we no longer need to worry about where we acquired it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see this happening. In research, it often happens that three or four different groups start working on the same experiment, but one of those groups gets it published first.  In this case, who should be the originator?  The fastest group?  The group with the best story?  Perhaps the experiment was conceived independently, or by attending the same thought-provoking lecture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing. Usually in my line of work, when I am presented new information, before I accept it as true, I weigh the quality of the source. This is not unlike the great number of researchers that preferentially read research articles from Nature, Science, and Cell (perhaps due to the potentially higher bar in peer review). Maybe this would really limit the number of genuinely new ideas I could potentially &quot;generate&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/05/23/Kleptomnesia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/05/23/Kleptomnesia/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Withings And Nest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Temperature is a key environmental factor in getting the best sleep. If it is too hot or too cold, people won&#39;t be able to sleep. They&#39;ll look to the cooler side of the pillow.  They&#39;ll twist and turn. It would be much easier if the room could alter bedroom temperature seamlessly through the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Withings has a sleep detector, and Nest has a thermostat. But both devices are not just the traditional hardware that have existed for the last 50 years. They have wireless communications, and can talk to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&#39;s the software magic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Aura has detected that a user is asleep, it will send a notification to your Nest thermostat to adjust the temperature to fall between 64.4-68° Fahrenheit, the best range for sleeping. When Aura senses that you haven woken up, it will communicate this information to Nest so that the temperature can return back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to examine how users&#39; quality of sleep improves over time with this system. After all, it is the ultimate test of this new product enhancement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//sleep/2015/05/11/withings-and-nest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//sleep/2015/05/11/withings-and-nest/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Start A Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startupclass.samaltman.com/courses/lec01/&quot;&gt;Lecture 1: How to Start a Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://genius.com/Sam-altman-lecture-1-how-to-start-a-startup-annotated&quot;&gt;Transcript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;starting a business where the goal is hyper growth and eventually building a very large company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your reason to have this goal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should only start a startup if you feel compelled by a particular problem and that you think starting a company is the best way to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The necessary (but not sufficient) conditions for achieving the goal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need a great idea, a great product, a great team, and great execution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And great execution is at least ten times as important and a hundred times harder than a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... someday you need to build a business that is difficult to replicate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they sounded really good, there would be too many people working on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another somewhat counterintuitive thing about good startup ideas is that they&#39;re almost always very easy to explain and very easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On initial market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have to find a small market in which you can get a monopoly and then quickly expand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common mistake among founders, especially first time founders, is that they think the first version of their product - the first version of their idea - needs to sound really big. But it doesn&#39;t. It needs to take over a small specific market and expand from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to invest in a company that&#39;s going after a small, but rapidly growing market, than a big, but slow-growing market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big advantages of these sorts of markets - these smaller, rapidly growing markets - is that customers are usually pretty desperate for a solution, and they&#39;ll put up with an imperfect, but rapidly improving product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can basically change everything in a start-up but the market, so you should actually do some thinking to be sure - or be as sure as you can be - that the market you&#39;re going after is going to grow and be there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On timing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sequoia&#39;s famous question: Why now? Why is this the perfect time for this particular idea, and to start this particular company. Why couldn&#39;t it be done two years ago, and why will two years in the future be two late?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good startups usually take ten years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most other problems that founders are trying to solve, raising money, getting more press, hiring, business development, et cetera, these are significantly easier when you have a great product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making something that people want, but only a medium amount, is a great way to fail, and not understand why you&#39;re failing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build something that a small number of users love. It is much easier to expand from something that small number of people love, to something that a lot of people love, then from something that a lot of people like to a lot of people love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get something people love, people will tell their friends about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need some users to help with the feedback cycle, but the way you should get those users is manually—you should go recruit them by hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... remember that the goal is to get a small group of them to love you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On simple initial product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another piece of advice to make something that users love: start with something simple. Its much much easier to make a great product if you have something simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its much much easier to make a great product if you have something simple. Even if your eventual plans are super complex, and hopefully they are, you can almost always start with a smaller subset of the problem then you think is the smallest, and its hard to build a great product, so you want to start with as little surface area as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason that simple&#39;s good is because it forces you to do one thing extremely well and you have to do that to make something that people love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dustin Moskovitz on being a founder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben Horowitz likes to say the number one role of a CEO is managing your own psychology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your team will really signal off of what you&#39;re bringing to the table. So if you take your foot off the gas, so will they.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil Libin on running a company:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The life of most CEOs is reporting to everyone else,
at least that’s what it feels like to me and most CEOs I know. If you want to exercise power and authority over people, join the military or go into politics. Don’t be an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dustin Moskovitz on reasons for starting a company:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One is you&#39;re so passionate about it that you have to do it and you&#39;re going to do it anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is important, that it&#39;s going to make the world better, so the world needs it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the world needs you to do it. You&#39;re actually well suited for this problem in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see the impact it was having at Facebook, we were convinced it was valuable to the world. We were also convinced no one else was going to build it, the problem had been around a long time and we just kept seeing incremental solutions to it and so we believed if we didn&#39;t come out with the solution we thought was best, there would be a lot of value left on the table. We couldn&#39;t stop working on it and literally the idea was beating itself out of our chests and forcing itself out into the world. And I think that&#39;s really the feeling you should be looking for when you start a company, that&#39;s how you know you have the right idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/25/how-to-start-a-startup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/25/how-to-start-a-startup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Operate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startupclass.samaltman.com/courses/lec14&quot;&gt;Lecture 14: How to Operate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://genius.com/Keith-rabois-lecture-14-how-to-operate-annotated&quot;&gt;Transcript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building a company is basically like taking all the irrational people you know putting them in one building, and then living with them twelve hours a day at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically what you are doing when building a company is building an engine. ... Eventually you want to construct a very high performance machine. A machine that almost nobody really has to worry about every hour, every minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... when you start a company everything is going to feel like a mess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On being an editor rather than a writer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So one of the most important things I learned at Square is the concept of editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically eliminating things, the biggest task of an editor is to simplify, simplify, simplify and that usually means omitting things. So that&#39;s your job too, is to clarify and simplify for everybody on your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second thing editors do, is they ask you clarifying questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the next thing you do is you allocate resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who work with you, generally, should be coming up with their own initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one way of measuring how well you are doing at communicating or talking to your colleagues about what&#39;s important and what&#39;s not, about why some things are important and why some things are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... the job of an editor is to ensure consistent voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, your company should feel, on your website, on PR releases, on your packaging if it&#39;s a physical product, anywhere on your recruiting pages it should feel like it was written by one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So just like the other metaphor on editing is writers do most of the work in the world, editors are not writing most of the content in any publication&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On managing employees:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any executive, any CEO, should not have one management style. Your management style should be dictated by your employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s times when you know something is a mistake and there&#39;s times when you wouldn&#39;t really do it that way but you have no idea whether it&#39;s the right or wrong answer. And then there is a consequence dimension. There are things that if you make the wrong decision are very catastrophic to your company and you will fail. There are things that are pretty low impact. At the end of the day they aren&#39;t really going to make a big difference, at least initially.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On hiring employees:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you hire more engineers you don&#39;t get that much more done. You actually sometimes get less done. You hire more designers, you definitely don&#39;t get more done, you get less done in a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/25/how-to-operate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/25/how-to-operate/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Negotiation Literature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are three books that help their readers navigate the process of negotiating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Yes-Negotiating-Agreement-Without/dp/0143118757&quot;&gt;Getting to Yes&lt;/a&gt;, by Roger Fisher &amp;amp; William Ury. This book advocates finding win-win outcomes among participants. Description from Amazon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting to Yes offers a proven, step-by-step strategy for coming to mutually acceptable agreements in every sort of conflict. Thoroughly updated and revised, it offers readers a straight-forward, universally applicable method for negotiating personal and professional disputes without getting angry-or getting taken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0143036971&quot;&gt;Bargaining for Advantage&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Shell. An Amazon review by David Landis had an interesting comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is the best work on the topic of the information parties exchange as part of the negotiation process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Power-Nice-Negotiate-Everyone-Especially-ebook/dp/B00SEBEBSO&quot;&gt;The Power of Nice&lt;/a&gt;, by Ronald Shapiro. In this book, Shapiro warns readers that winner-take-all negotiation may be effective at a given time, but the winner can subsequently miss out on opportunities for future business. Shapiro summarizes his process for negotiating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preparing better than the other side; probing so you know what they want and why; and proposing, ideally without going first and revealing too much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/13/negotiation-literature/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//organization/2015/04/13/negotiation-literature/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mostlycurious Search</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mostlycurious.com is a static Jekyll site hosted on Github.  This has been pretty convenient compared to my prior efforts, which have included Posterous, Tumblr, Ghost. One thing I have always wanted to include was a site-specific search bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a new problem, and a quick search led me to a previously answered &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10131541/how-can-i-add-a-site-search-feature-to-a-jekyll-blog&quot;&gt;Stackoverflow post&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://cse.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google custom search&lt;/a&gt;, because it seems pretty easy for a first attempt (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-04-11-google-custom-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Output script&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the web there is another good example and walkthrough from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bahmutov.calepin.co/search-across-my-blog-posts-and-github-projects.html&quot;&gt;Gleb Bahmutov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//2015/04/11/mostlycurious-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//2015/04/11/mostlycurious-search/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cohen&#39;s D Visualized</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kristoffer Magnussen has a neat blog about statistics and psychology at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rpsychologist.com/d3/cohend/&quot;&gt;R &amp;lt;- Psychologist&lt;/a&gt;.  In particular, he has a very useful visualization of a metric called Cohen&#39;s d.  Even if you know what that is, it&#39;s very helpful to have a quick tool on hand without having to calculate anything.  All of the visualization appears to be made from &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org&quot;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt;, which is becoming a standard for showing your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-04-03-cohen-d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//science/2015/04/03/cohen%27s-d-visualized/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//science/2015/04/03/cohen%27s-d-visualized/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Matlab Files On Github</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, I&#39;ll be distributing various Matlab programs that I&#39;ve used to analyze scientific data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/03/28/my-matlab-files-on-github/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/03/28/my-matlab-files-on-github/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Windows+p</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows 8 has a nice shortcut, that&#39;s actually been on previous versions, but I&#39;ve just discovered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Windows logo + p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/2015-03-25-screen-options.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one shortcut, by quickly allowing you to toggle between duplicating and extending across monitors, simultaneously kills two of my annoyances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever had to give a presentation and not be able to control your presentation view? (perhaps due to some ATI or nVIDIA driver that overrides Windows native display control)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever use Chrome remote desktop to a machine with dual monitors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/03/25/windows%2BP/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rpjb.github.com//productivity/2015/03/25/windows%2BP/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
